Indiana University Folklore Institute Material Culture papers, 1953-1984, bulk 1960-1981 C614
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Folklore Institute Material Culture papers
1953-1984
1960-1981
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University, Bloomington. Folklore Institute
C614
9.4 cubic feet 10 boxes
The Indiana University Folklore Institute is an active center of folklore scholarship and has a long history of collecting oral literature and arts. This collection consists of papers written on a variety of material culture topics by students taking courses in the Folklore Institute. These papers are dated roughly between 1960 through the early 1980s.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Advance notice is required.
Administrative History
The Folklore Institute at Indiana University began as an eight-week program in the summer of 1942 under the directorship of Professor Stith Thompson. From June 29 to August 22 of that year residential and visiting faculty taught courses, which carried university credit, on a number of topics. Course topics ranged from an introductory course on folklore to field collecting and recording to the folk tale and similar forms. Others covered folk song and folk music as well as Native American folklore.
The Folklore Institute grew into a stable research branch of Indiana University's College of Arts and Sciences in 1949 and received departmental status with an independent faculty in 1963; however, the Graduate School first listed M.A. and Ph.D. degrees in Folklore for the academic year of 1949-1950 Since the academic year of 1971-1972 the Institute has offered an undergraduate degree in folklore as well. The Institute has also had a long history with research and teaching interests in ethnomusicology. In 2000 the Ethnomusicology Institute was created and merged with the Folklore Institute to become the Department of Folklore and Ethnomusicology, which now offers undergraduate and graduate degrees in both fields.
Arrangement
This collection consists of papers collected by students within the Folklore Institute in Indiana University's Department of Folklore & Ethnomusicology, arranged chronologically.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of papers written by students at the Folklore Institute at Indiana University, Bloomington mostly from the 1960s through the early 1980s The files are arranged in numerical order (which was originally assigned by the Folklore Archive at the time of accessioning), which is also roughly chronological order. Accompanying materials such as cassette tapes are housed separately.
There are a number of different subjects represented including, but not limited to, architecture, craft, tombstones & epitaphs, quilting, furniture, instrument making, family traditions and recipes, fashion, and food ways. Many of these papers consist of interviews with artisans and craftsmen, family members, or owners of the locations being researched. One such paper includes an account by the owner of a house near Elizabethtown Indiana which was part of the Underground Railroad used by escaped enslaved people going north to Canada during the Civil War. For those interested in more religious studies, there is a paper on food and religious practices of the Russian Orthodox Church during the week of Easter. There are also a fair number of papers written on local tombstones and instrument makers. Apple doll making and water witching seem to have been popular subjects in the sixties and seventies.
A number of the locations and craftsmen discussed are local or in close proximity to Bloomington, including a paper on the Rose Well House which is a popular fixture of legend in IU campus lore.
Most papers include samples or photographs related to the paper's subject. One paper written on coalmining in Sullivan County Indiana has a particularly interesting set of photos of coal miners and the coal mining complex. Other papers contain clippings from magazines, maps, quilt square samples, illustrations, and similar objects -- one paper written on the Kennedy family, builders of covered bridges in Indiana, has a beautiful set of covered bridge illustrations and diagrams.
Separated Material
32 analog audio cassette tapes and 1 quarter inch analog open reel recording tape located in box 10.
Related Material
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database: http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesphotos/
Acquisition Information
2003/055
Provenance
Transferred to the IU Archives in 2003 by John McDowell, Chair of Folklore Department.
College students' writings, American--Indiana--Bloomington.; Material culture--Indiana.; Decorative arts--Indiana.; Architecture--Indiana.; Indiana University, Bloomington. Folklore Institute -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. Folklore Institute -- Records and correspondence
- Student Papers (Box 1)
  - M/C 60/1 Weedle, Gary W. "Introduction to Folklore A Collection" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Architecture, Church), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, Date Unknown (Box 1)
  - M/C 60/2 Gritzbaugh, Cheryl. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana – Architecture, Barn), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, Date Unknown. (Box 1)
  - M/C 60/2 Gritzbaugh, Cheryl. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana – Architecture, Barn), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, Date Unknown (Box 1)
  - M/C 61/1.1 Hunter, John T. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana & Michigan – Carving), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown (?)., 1953 (Box 1)
  - M/C 61/.2 61/1.2 Smith, Mrs. Barbara A. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Carving), L383, Instructor Unknown, November 28, 1961 (Box 1)
  - M/C 61/1.3 Walls, Ann. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Carving), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown (?)., Fall 1959 (Box 1)
  - M/C 61/2 Smith, Barbara A. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Quilts), L383, Instructor Unknown, November 28, 1961 (Box 1)
  - M/C 61/3 Smith, Barbara A. "Weavers Contact in the Bloomington Vicinity" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Weaving, Rugs), L383, November 28, 1961 (Box 1)
  - M/C 61/4 Edgerton, Susan Conrad. "The Queer Tomb Stone" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Tombstones), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown(?)., 1961 (Box 1)
  - M/C 61/5 Smith, Mrs. Barbara A. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana – Furniture), L383, Instructor Unknown, November 28, 1961 (Box 1)
  - M/C 62/1 Adams, Charles S. "A Folk Architectural Tradition in Southern Indiana" (Norther America, U.S., Indiana - Architecture, Houses, Soap Box), F801, Dr. Roberts, January 1962 (Box 1)
  - M/C 63/1 Patterson, John. "Salt Creek Architecture" (Norther America, U.S., Indiana - Architecture, House & Log Cabin), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, January 1962 (Box 1)
  - M/C 63/2 Greenlee, Betsy. "A Household Craft: Needlework of Bloomington and Vicinity" (North America, U.S, Indiana & Illinois - Craft, Needlework), F801, Instructor Unknown, May 22, 1963 (Box 1)
  - M/C 64/1 Jones, Michael Owen. "Folk Toys" (North America, U.S, Indiana & Kansas - Craft, Toys, Games), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1964 (Box 1)
  - M/C 65/1 Gibson, Evelyn E (?). "The Old Fashioned Hairpin" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Food Preservation & Loom), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown (?), 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 65/2 Vaughn, Judith. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Crafts, General), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 65/3 Unknown Author. Not Title. (North America, U.S., Indiana - Looms), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 65/4 Perez, Kathleen. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Needlework), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 65/5 Vaughn, Judith. No Title. (North America, U.S., Indiana - Craft, Chair Weaving), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 65/6 Brown, James D. "Traditional Instrument Making (Violin/Dulcimer)" (Floyd Stafford - carpenter, Max Wilson - philosophy student at IU, North America, U.S., Indiana - Craft, Music Instruction), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, November 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 65/7 Koontz, Jill. (Floyd Stafford - carpenter, Max G. Wilson - student, North America, U.S., Indiana - Craft, Musical Instrument, & Tools), Introduction to Folklore, Instructor Unknown, December 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 65/8 Unknown Author. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Furniture), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 65/9 Swanson, Diana. "Barn Signs: Hex or Decoration" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Barns Signs), F220, Instructor Unknown(?)., 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 65/10 Cravey, Georgia. "Traditional Pie Crust Designs Among Female Descendants of the Parker Family" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Craft, Food, Pie Crusts, Designs), F201, Instructor Unknown(?)., 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 65/11 Reahard, Thomas Rex. "The Blacksmith and Farrier" (North America, U.S., Indiana), F801, Dr. Warren Roberts (?), August 12, 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 65/12 Potts, Kenneth. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana), F201, Instructor Unknown, Fall 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/1 Gritzbaugh, Cheryl. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Food Tools, etc.), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1966 (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/2 Welsch, Roger L. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana & Nebraska - Architecture, Barns), Class # Unknown, Dr. Roberts, 1966 (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/3 Hohn, Mills. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Architecture, Bridges), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1966 (?) (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/4 Unknown Author. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Occupation, Blacksmith), Class # Unknown, Dr. Roberts, 1966 (?) (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/5 Unknown Author. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Cobbler tools), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1966 (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/6 Mills, John. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Architecture, Mills), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1966 (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/7 Gritzbaugh, Cheryl. (North America, U.S., Indiana - Quilts), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1966 (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/8 Freese, Donald G. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana – Tools, farm & carpentry), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1966 (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/10 Hawley, Steve. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana – Woodworking), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1966 (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/11 Hershberger, Allen. No Title. "A Short History of Forebay Barn" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Architecture, Barn, Amish, Forebay), F801, Instructor Unknown, 1966 (?) (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/12 Clements, William M. "Apple Cider Production in the Folklife of Southern Indiana" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Craft, Food, Apple, Cider Making), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1966 (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/13 Taylor, Lela V., "Quilts" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Quilts), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1966 (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/14 Cerven, James, "Pana Folklore" (North America, U.S., Illinois – Remedies, Folktales, Games, Sayings, Beliefs, Farm Beliefs, Water Witching), GSC313, Instructor Jordan (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/15 Rawlinson, Mike, "Folklore Collection from White County Illinois" (North America, U.S., Illinois – Ghost Stories, Superstitions), F313, Instructor Unknown (Box 1)
  - M/C 66/16 Wirtel, Anthony, "Games of Illinois" (North America, U.S., Illinois – Games), F313, Instructor Jordan (Box 1)
  - 67/285 Martin, John R. "Collection of Epitaphs with Verses on Them" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Tombstones, Epitaphs), F384, Dr. Gladys Fry, August 7, 1967 (Box 1)
  - 67/286 Christoph, John. "Uses of the Two Front Doors in Traditional Homes of the Midwest" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Architecture, Houses), F384, Barbro Sklute (?), 1967 (Box 1)
  - 68/143 Dougherty, William R and Dabney Sharron Bourdon. (North America, U.S., Indiana – Furniture, Quilts, Farm Implements), Class # Unknown, Dr. Warren Roberts, January 5, 1968 (Box 1)
  - 68/121 Linthicum, Frances. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana – Misc. Cloth Craft), F384, Dr. Warren Roberts, December 30, 1967 (Box 1)
  - 68/142 Black, Judith Ellen. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana – Quilts and Rugs), F384, Dr. Warren Roberts, January 5, 1968 (Box 1)
  - 68/290 Wees, Dustin. "An Example of Traditional Architecture" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Architecture, House), Class # Unknown, Roberts, January 18, 1968 (Box 1)
  - M/C 68/7 Stoll, Christel J. "Collection Project for American Folklore, F384" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Tombstones & Architecture), F384, Dr. Warren Roberts, January 5, 1968 (Box 1)
  - M/C 68/8 Breitweiser, Francis. "Mushroom Hunting" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Mushroom Hunting), F201, Dr. Linda Degh, May 1968 (Box 1)
  - M/C 68/9 Broemmelsick, Patricia. "Folklore Collection" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Tools, Cooking Utensils), F201, Dr. Linda Degh, May 20, 1968 (Box 1)
  - M/C 68/10 Carlson, Lynn. "Folklore Collection" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Weaving), F201, Dr. Linda Degh, May 25, 1968 (Box 1)
  - M/C 68/11 Smtih, Theresa M. "Gravestones and Epitaphs" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Tombstones & Epitaphs), F384, Fry, August 1968 (Box 1)
  - M/C 68/12 Gubbins, Christine. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana – Recipes & Soap Making), F384, Fry, 1968 (Box 1)
  - M/C 68/13 Hines, Donald. (North America, U.S., Indiana – Tombstones), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1968 (Box 1)
  - M/C 68/14 Baker, Chuck. "A Study of the Longrifle in its Northampton County Pennsylvania Form, including a survey of several specific makers, and an introduction and guide for study of this area of folklore" (North America, U.S., Pennsylvania – Craft, Long Rifle, Design), Class # Unknown, Instructor Uknown, 1968 (Box 1)
  - M/C 69/1 Smeltzer, Frances. "Gingerbread and Tower Houses" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Architecture, House & Barn), Class # Unknown, Roberts, January 7, 1965 (Box 1)
  - M/C 69/2 Chamber, Richard W. "Early Schoolhouses of Boone County, Indiana" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Architecture, Schoolhouses), American Folklore, Mr. Rosenberg, August 8, 1966 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/3 Upadhaya, Hari Shanker. "Some American Folk Charis" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Furniture, Chairs), Class # Unknown, W. E. Roberts, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/4 Collura, Concetta M. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana – Farming Tools, Slides), Class # Unknown, Roberts, August 1962 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/5 Jahn, Caroline. "Tombstones and Epitaphs in Central & Southern Indiana" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Tombstones & Epitaphs), American Folklore, Instructor Unknown, June 1966 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/6 DuVall, Don. "The Cornelison Pottery" (North America, U.S., Kentucky, Bybee - Pottery), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/7 Smeltzer, Barbara. "Quilting" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Architecture, Cloth, slides), Folk Arts & Crafts, Roberts, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/8 Mullarky, Magnus Einarsson. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana – Industry, Sorghum Syrup), Class # Unknown, Roberts, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/10 Horack, Sarah F. "Tradition in the Graveyard Monroe County, Indiana" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Tombstones), F801, Dr. Roberts, Summer 1966 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/11 Lewis, Mary Ellen Brown. "Clocks—Mostly American" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Clocks), F801, Roberts, Spring 1965 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/12 Reuss, Dick. "Old Time Cabinet Making in Bloomington a historical survey by Dick Reuss" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Cabinetmaking), F801, Dr. Roberts, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/13 El-Shamy, Hassan. "Notes on Furniture and Other Items Found Around Bloomington" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Furniture & Misc), Class # Unknown, Dr. Roberts, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/14 Hattendork, Joan. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Furniture & Tools), Class # Unknown, Dr. Roberts, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/17 Beldars, Veldre. "Latvian Folk Costume" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Clothing, Latvian), Class # Unknown, Dr. Roberts, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/18 Skulte, Barbro. "Nineteenth Century Handmade Looms in Bloomington and its Vicinity" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Weaving & Associated Tools), F801, Dr. Roberts, May 15, 1963 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/19 Rupe, Bill. "American Folklore F-384 Term Project" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Craft, Mailboxes), F384, Dr. Roberts, May 24, 1966 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/20 Tisserand, Charles A. "Folk Toys in America" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Toys & Dolls), F801, Dr. Roberts, January 2, 1962 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/21 Rafert, John. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Tombstone & Epitaphs), Class # Unknown, Dr. Roberts, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/22 Hart, Lawrence. "Houses that Last Till Doomsday" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Tombstone & Epitaphs), Class # Unknown, Mr. Aceves, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/23 Part I Ritch, Betty. "Quilting in Monroe County, Indiana" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Quilts), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, August 1966 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/23 Part II Ritch, Betty. "Quilting in Monroe County, Indiana" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Quilts), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown, August 1966 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/24 Shelton, Bruce L. "Gravestones and Markers A Study of Designs and Symbols 1800-1900" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Tombstones), Class # Unknown, Dr. Roberts, 1965 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/26 Coleman, Jon & John Lair. "Some Observations of a Tradition - Oriented Family" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Butchering, Architecture, Tools), F801, Dr. Roberts, Fall 1967 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/27 Blaustein, Richard. "Design and Technique in American Folk Instruments and Problems of Esthetic Pressure" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Musical Instruments), F801, Dr. Roberts, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/28 Orr, Inge C. "Early Stone and Brick Houses of the Mid Wabash Valley" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Architecture, House, Brick & Stone), Class # Unknown, Dr. Roberts, January 1968 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/29 Chen de Yearwood, Shou-hua. "Folk Life Traditions of Mrs. Dora Hash" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Quilts & Misc.), Folk Arts Crafts and Architecture, Dr. Warren Roberts, Fall 1967 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/30 Samuel, Susan. "Woven Rag Rugs" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Weaving, Rugs), Folk Arts Crafts and Architecture, Dr. Warren Roberts, August 1968 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/31 Buehler, R. E. "Food Preservation Methods, etc." (North America, U.S., Indiana - Food Preservation Methods), F801, Dr. Roberts, January 10, 1961 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/32 Rosenberg, Neil. "Instrument Making in Southern Indiana, the Bedford-Oolitic-Harrodsburg Region" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Musical Instruments), Folk Arts Craft and Architecture, Dr. Warren Roberts, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/33 Smeltzer, Frances. "Tombstones" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Tombstones & Epitaphs), Class # Unknown, Dr. Roberts, May 25, 1965 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/35 Blatt, Morton. "Epithets" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Tombstone & Epitaphs), Class # Unknown, Dr. Roberts, December 4, 1968 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/36 Moorhead, Kathy and Andy McKee. "Collecting Project: Epitaphs and Rubbings" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Tombstones & Rubbings), F201, Dr. Fry, May 17, 1968 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/37 Hainz, Sandra. "Quilt Pattern Collection" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Quilt Designs), F384, Dr. Roberts, Dec. 4, 1968 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/38 Robert, Michael J. "A Pictorial Collection of Mrs. Regina Ernst's Handkerchiefs with Crocheted Edges" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Crochet & Needlework), F384, Dr. Warren Roberts, January 4, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/39 Dean, Peter G. "Miss Rosan Jordan" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Interior Décor, Hippie), F384, May 6, 1968 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/40 Van De Keere. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Recipes), F201, Dr. Fry, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/41 Grocke, Vicky L. "Covered Bridges" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Architecture, Bridges), F201, Fry, 1969 (Box 2)
  - M/C 69/42 McLemore, Sara. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Tombstones & Epitaphs), F201, Dr. Fry, 1969 (Box 3)
  - M/C 69/43 Leach, Janiece. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Tombstones & Eptiaphs), F201, Dr. Fry, 1969 (Box 3)
  - M/C 69/44 Attagar, Kingkeo, Hasan El-Shamy, & Laura Samuelson. "A Cooperative Project Concerning the Traditional Architecture and House-hold Artifacts of the Bloomington Area" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Architecture, Bloomington, Comprehensive overview with house artifacts), F801, Dr. Roberts, Fall 1961 (Box 3)
  - M/C 68/45 Downing, David. "The Kennedys: Covered Bridge Builders" (North America, U.S., Indiana – Architecture, Bridges, Covered), F101, John Vlach, Date Unknown (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/1 Robbins, Kimbal. "Folklore Research Paper A Study of Bloomington's Quarries" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Quarries), F201, Mary Wolff, 1970 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/2 Read, Rodney B. "A Study of the Limestone Industry with a Particular Emphasis on the Art of Carving Limestone" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Carving, Stone & Quarrying), F384, Dr. Roberts, Dec. 12, 1969 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/3 Tucker, Paul. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Tombstones), F384, Dr. Roberts, 1969 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/4 Ruhl, Stephen. No Title (North America, U.S., Indiana - Rugs, Weaving, Rag), F384, Dr. Roberts, 1969 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/5 Wells, Barbara. "Folklore Collection Tombstones - Circa 1688-1892" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Tombstones), F384, Dr. Roberts, Dec. 18, 1969 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/6 Grimes, Jennifer Y. "Soul Food" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Soul Food), F384, Dr. Roberts, Dec. 3, 1969 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/7 Fraps, Barbara. "A Hoosier Bank Barn" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Architecture, Barn), F384, Dr. Roberts, Dec. 2, 1969 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/8 Benjamin, Joyce. "The Weaving Craft" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Rugs & Loom), F384, Dr. Roberts, 1969 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/10 Brown, Rebecca. "Farm Architecture in Jackson County" (North America, U.S., Illinois - Architecture, Barn, House), F384, Dr. Roberts, December 3, 1969 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/11 Wolfe, Donald M. (North America, U.S., Indiana - Architecture, Frames, Tools), F384, Dr. Roberts, Dec. 18, 1969 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/12 Mowson, Jan. "Traditional Crafts Weaving Hooked Rugs Spinning" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Weaving), F384, Dr. Roberts, Dec. 3, 1969 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/14 Unknown Author. "Terre Haute: The Lasting Impression of Coal Minning Upon Local Culture" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Coal Mining), Class # Unknown, Instructor Unknown(?)., 1970 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/15 Fogel, Janet. "Folklore Final Project" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Furniture & Architecture), F220, Glassie, 1971 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/16 Greenberg, Andrea. "A Breif Study of Two Bloomington Houses" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Architecture, House), Material Culture, Instructor Unknown, May 1970 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/17 Stroup, Robert. "One of the Last Surviving Handcrafts Pipe Making" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Craft, Pipe Making), Folklore, Miss Mary Wolff, Jan. 14, 1970 (Box 3)
  - M/C 70/224 Short, Robert Lowell. No Title. (North America, U.S., Indiana), F384, Mrs. Ridlen, May 1970 (Box 3)
  - M/C 71/1 Dasanayaka, Stanley & Jim Jontz. "The Romance of the Broom a study of broom making in Kentucky and Ceylon" (North America, U.S., Kentucky, Celon - Broom making), F391, Dr. Roberts, Fall 1971 (Box 3)
  - M/C 71/5 Sample, Patricia E. "The Cabin Craftsman center Nashville, Indiana" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Craftsman Center in Nashville), F720/F721, Dr. Warren Roberts, August 13, 1971 (Box 3)
  - M/C 71/6 Thigpen, Kenneth & Bruce Giuliano. "Log Structures in Van Buren Township Field Work Project" (North America, U.S., Indiana - Architecture, Log), Material Culture, Dr. Roberts, June 4, 1971 (Box 3)